The world belongs to the weird.
Weird: The Al Yankovic Story is a music, comedy film directed by Eric Appel.
Exploring every facet of ‘Weird Al’ Yankovic’s life, from his meteoric rise to fame with early hits like ‘Eat It’ and ‘Like a Surgeon’ to his torrid celebrity love affairs and famously depraved
lifestyle, this biopic takes audiences on a truly unbelievable journey through Yankovic’s life and career, from gifted child prodigy to the greatest musical legend of all time.
'Weird Al' Yankovic, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Madonna, played by Evan Rachel Wood.
Dr. Demento, played by Rainn Wilson.
Nick Yankovic, played by Toby Huss.
Jim, played by Jack Lancaster.
Steve, played by Spencer Treat Clark.
Weird: The Al Yankovic Story is a 2022 American biographical musical parody film directed by Eric
Appel, in his feature directorial debut, from a screenplay he co-wrote with Al Yankovic.
The film is a satire on musical biopics and is loosely based on Yankovic's
life and career as an accordionist and parody songwriter.
It stars Daniel Radcliffe as Yankovic, along with Evan Rachel Wood, Rainn
Wilson, Toby Huss and Julianne Nicholson in supporting roles.
A fake trailer for a satirical biographical film was
produced by Appel for Funny or Die in 2010.
Yankovic would screen the trailer at his concerts, which made fans question when a full-length film
would be made and led Yankovic and Appel to develop the film's concept together.
Weird: The Al Yankovic Story was filmed on a budget of around $8
million over eighteen days between February and March 2022.
It premiered at the 2022 Toronto International Film Festival on September 8,
and was released on The Roku Channel on November 4, 2022.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who largely praised its
screenplay, humor, and cast performances (particularly Radcliffe).
At the 75th Primetime Emmy Awards, Yankovic and Appel's script was nominated for Outstanding Writing for a Limited or Anthology Series
or Movie and Radcliffe's performance was nominated for Outstanding Lead Actor in a Limited or Anthology Series or Movie.
The film won the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Television Movie.
The film explores themes of musician, accordion, parody,
duringcreditsstinger, based on myths, legends or folklore.
The tone is lighthearted.